A Guide to the Herbert O. Blunt Collection, 1929-1946
Virginia Room, Fairfax County Public Library
The Herbert O. Blunt Collection, 1929-1946
Fairfax County Public Library
MSS 06-113
22.5 linear feet
The Herbert O. Blunt Collection consists of 22.5 linear feet, spans the years 1929-1946, and contains 31 notebooks featuring news articles written by Blunt as the Fairfax County news editor for the Alexandria Gazette newspaper.
Blunt, Herbert O. (1896-1975)
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
None
Acquisition Information
Donated by Susan Norman, December 2021.
Historical and Biographical Information
Herbert Oliver Blunt was born on September 18, 1896, in Fairfax, Virginia to Henry H. Blunt and Janet “Nettie” L. Pulman. He was the oldest of two sisters and a brother. Blunt was working for the Cranford Paving Company based at Camp Humphreys (Fort Belvoir), before serving in the U.S. Army as a private during World War I. On May 1, 1918, he married Ruth E. Hott in Washington, D.C.
In 1926, Blunt became a reporter and Fairfax County news editor for the Alexandria Gazette newspaper. As the Fairfax correspondent, Blunt wrote a “Fairfax County News” column in addition to writing numerous articles about county events. After being associated with the newspaper for 17 years, publisher C.C. Carlin Jr. appointed Blunt as managing editor of the Alexandria Gazette and Arlington Daily newspapers in 1943. He retired from the position in 1946.
In addition to being a reporter, Blunt engaged in local civic affairs throughout his life. He was the American Legion’s vice commander for Alexandria Post 24, and a member of American Legion and Voiture Locale No. 934, the Forty and Eight Society, Mt. Vernon Grange, Chamber of Commerce, and an officer in the Groveton Community Club. In 1940, he became the first chairman of the Fairfax County Selective Service System and held that position throughout World War II.
Scope and Content
The Herbert O. Blunt Collection consists of 22.5 linear feet, spans the years 1929-1946, and contains 31 notebooks featuring news articles written by Blunt as the Fairfax County news editor for the Alexandria Gazette newspaper. Subjects of Blunt’s articles include the courts, schools, politics, elections, accidents, police, crime, murders, fires, jail breaks, weather, obituaries, roadwork, infrastructure, clubs, building permits, marriage licenses, and local soldiers fighting overseas during World War II.
Adjunct Descriptive Data
None
None
Index Terms
Alexandria (Va.) -- Newspapers.; Blunt, Herbert O. (1896-1975).; Fairfax County (Va.) -- History.
Container List
- Notebook, "Accidents 1929-30-31", 1929-1931 (Box 1)
- Notebook, "Fairfax 1929-30", 1929-1930 (Box 1)
- Notebook, "Police 1929-30", 1929-1930 (Box 1)
- Notebook, "Supervisors 1929-30-31-32-33", 1929-1933 (Box 1)
- Notebook, "1930", 1930-1931 (Box 1)
- Notebook, "1930 II", 1930 (Box 1)
- Notebook, "1931 County Column", 1931 (Box 1)
- Notebook, "1932", 1932 (Box 1)
- Notebook, "1933 County Column", 1933 (Box 1)
- Notebook, "1933", 1933 (Box 1)
- Notebook, "1933", 1933 (Box 1)
- Notebook, 1934 (Box 2)
- Notebook, "1934 County Column", 1934 (Box 2)
- Notebook, "1935 County Column", 1935 (Box 2)
- Notebook, "1936 County Column", 1936 (Box 2)
- Notebook, "1937", 1937 (Box 2)
- Notebook, "1937", 1937 (Box 2)
- Notebook, "Jul-Dec 1938 County Column", 1938 (Box 2)
- Notebook, "Fairfax 1940 Vol. 2", 1940 (Box 2)
- Notebook, "1941", 1941 (Box 2)
- Notebook, "Prince William 1941-42-43", 1941-1943 (Box 3)
- Notebook, "Fairfax 1942", 1942 (Box 3)
- Notebook, "Fairfax 1942 Vol. 2", 1942 (Box 3)
- Notebook, "1943", 1943 (Box 3)
- Notebook [contains local WWII soldier news], 1943-1945 (Box 3)
- Notebook, "Fairfax Jan-June 1944", 1944 (Box 3)
- Notebook, "Fairfax 1944", 1944 (Box 3)
- Notebook ["Home Town Roundup" column], 1944-1945 (Box 3)
- Notebook, "1945", 1945 (Box 3)
- Notebook, "Fairfax Jul-Dec 1945", 1945 (Box 3)
- Notebook, "1946", 1946 (Box 3)